# **BENJAMIN CORREIRA**

Manager of Operations

114 Williams St, Longmeadow, MA 01106 •

(413) 455-8313 •

bencorreira@hotmail.com •

linkedin.com/in/correib •

#### **SUMMARY**

High performing manager of operations, with experience in both Inbound and Outbound functions with both Warehouse Fulfillment and Logistics. Been part of warehouses turning up to 300,000+ in volume daily with inventory over \$1,000,000. Have also been part of delivery stations dispatching up to 60,000+ in volume daily. Extremely successful in people management and work culture, with prior direct reports ranging up to 250 or more and experience managing operations of over 300+. Capable of delivering results not only personally but with my team. Proven ability to gain trust of employees and leadership of all levels as well as internal/external support teams. Able to support existing projects, or projects from launch.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE .....

## AMAZON LOGISTICS - Wilmington, MA and Windsor, CT

Manager of Operations, April 2020 - Present

- Developed multiple tools in both excel and python for operations leadership use on shift, now spread across 15 states.
- Managed up to 70 direct reports, maintaining safety first initiatives and positive employee culture, monitoring safety, training, quality, performance, and scheduling
- Part of station startup, achieving tied #1 benchmark launch for the year of 2020, also helped in the startup of a Fulfillment Center
- Assisted in the training of over 10 salaried operations leaders for various site launches around Massacshuestts

#### AMAZON FULFILLMENT - Windsor, CT

Outbound Operations Flow Lead -> Manager of Operations, August 2018 - April 2020

- Managed up to 250 direct reports, maintaining safety-first initiatives and positive employee culture
- Ran project helping site restore over \$15,000 of inventory to an available state and reduce continued turnover
- Oversaw Outbound operation of over 300 employees, including performance, labor allocation, building conveyance, and multiple daily sync meetings with leadership team
- Trained and supported senior leadership on Outbound operation across the site
- Helped kickstart site "University" classes for new/old salaried leadership, gave class on Associate Connection
- Site and specifically the shift was regional cost leader in the 2018 holiday season

# **SEARS - Springfield, MA**

Backroom Lead, September 2016 - September 2017

- Supported both ups shipment web orders of up to 100+ per shift, as well as web orders and customer pickups of up to 50+ per shift.
- Managed the receiving and unloading of all appliance and freight trailers

#### **EDUCATION**

### ADDITIONAL SKILLS .....

#### **Western Governors University - Online**

Bachelor of Science, IT Management, 2014-2016 Some college - Unfinished

- Proficient in MS Office, including Excel VBA
- Introductory HTML/CSS/Python/Java
- Web and tech savvy, require little to no training